<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://kush99993s.github.io/xml/base.min.xml" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>summary on Blog</title>
    <link>https://kush99993s.github.io/tags/summary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in summary on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 13:15:22 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kush99993s.github.io/tags/summary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Common mistakes in experimentation</title>
      <link>https://kush99993s.github.io/post/experimentation_mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 13:15:22 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kush99993s.github.io/post/experimentation_mistakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intro ==hook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goal == stackes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenets == stackes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current State == Setting and BackStory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lession Learned == Plot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stargegy == Plot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have monitor more than 40 experiments in this year, Here is one most common reason experiments fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Calling of Experiments too Early &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of time, it is most common discuss we had with stack holder, as soon as it looks like experiment reach significance level even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have statistical power. This is way power analysis upfront comes very useful. Ability to show that it is still not time is critical tool for data scientist how have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Difference between assignment and applied &lt;/h4&gt;
Some time Experiment start time and implimentation time can be different, it is critical know if there is difference. Example, if experimentation treatment need to be applied by human,for example, sales person talking to client. In this case, treatment is created long before applying it. Another Example, if you are using api call to get experimentation, sometimes, api call will fail or take longer than SLA, now, treatment suppose to be applied but it was not. 
&lt;h4&gt; Data Quality Control&lt;/h4&gt;
However, most common issues I have seen is with data quality control. Most of time, issues is with data collection or lack of data collections. Usally, data quality control is not normal part of software developer so it take some time for people to </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
